TOMMY ROSARIO

Seasoned Frontend Developer

tjrosario.github.io

Email: tomjasonrosario@gmail.com



ABOUT ME

I'm a frontend developer based out of the Jersey Shore. I love working on fun, innovative websites. I've been involved in technology for almost two decades now. I'm a bit of a perfectionist and take a lot of pride in all of my work. I try to leave every piece of code a bit more modular, performant and readable than how I found it.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

Plixer

Sep 2019 - Present

- Assisted in re-architecting network traffic analysis system from a legacy tech-stack to modern Angular 8+ framework
- Lead development on the application's reporting engine which gives customer's a clear visualization of all network conversation and device usage
- Components and services strongly typed using Typescript
- Wrote unit tests using Jasmine and Karma
- Implemented Bootstrap for the UI library

Tech Stack: Angular 8+, Typescript, Bootstrap

Frontend Engineer

CityBldr

May 2017 - August 2019

 Lead front end developer for both the consumer facing and internal RETech application that determines the best value and uses for land for both sellers and buyers.

SKILLS

Frontend

react | redux | angular | typescript esnext | javascript | scss | bootstrap material-ui | jest | enzyme | magento

Middle Tier

nodejs | express | passport | stripe

Backend

mongodb

Design

photoshop | zeplin

Project Management

jira | trello | zenhub

Repo Platforms

git | github | gitlab

EDUCATION

University of Delaware

Bachelors of Science, Computer Science

- Built property claim flow which allows sellers to register and look up their property to determine its worth when sold alone and along with neighbors
- Assisted in building home-grown CRM system that partners could use to manage leads and potential targets
- Helped build a target dispatching platform which automates the process of building a set of target properties for any particular lead run
- Facilitated ongoing upgrades to the front end stack (React)
- State management using Redux
- Implemented UI components with Material UI
- Lead efforts in the consumer-facing site redesign

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Material UI

Sr. UI Developer

AffinityX

Jan 2015 - May 2017

- Created new functionality and features for creative content delivery platforms using KnockoutJS, jQuery and PHP
- Helped in building custom application routing system
- Developed re-usable components using KnockoutJS
- Built a custom proofing interface that allows customers to upload creative content, manage revision history and mark for approval
- Assisted in building administrative console

Tech Stack: KnockoutJS, jQuery, PHP

Frontend Engineer

ThreadLab, Inc

May 2014 - Jan 2020

- Lead front end development using Angular 5+, SASS
- Built a proxy using NodeJS for restful API consumption
- Developed build pipeline with Jenkins
- Created responsive layout using SASS/Bourbon
- Implemented recurring subscription system using Recurly
- Integrated Stripe and Paypal payment funnels
- Manage email marketing templates via Mailchimp and Mandrill

Tech Stack: Angular 5+, Typescript, NodeJS, Bourbon

Software Engineer

Do Something

May 2014 – Jan 2015

- Lead development on various social awareness campaigns
- Creating new features, functionality to application modules using jQuery and RequireJS
- Ongoing maintenance within Drupal framework template system
- Contributed to open-sourced interface framework and pattern libraries

Tech Stack: Drupal 7, jQuery, RequireJS, Bourbon

Senior Software Engineer

CPXi

Oct 2013 - May 2014

- Worked on new functionality and features for company's internal metrics dashboard
- Developed browser plugins that were available in the

Chrome and Firefox web stores

- Lead UI development on a real-time news feed application / scraper built on HandlebarsJS, NodeJS, and Sails MVC
- Proprietary CSS framework using LESS

Tech Stack: Handlebars JS, Laravel, Symfony, LESS, NodeJS, Sails MVC

Frontend Tech Lead

Alexander Interactive

Jul 2006 - Oct 2013

- Built, managed and lead a team of seven front-end developers
- In charge of providing front-end development estimates on all projects
- Developed and re-wrote several re-usable JavaScript widgets from Prototype JS to jQuery
- Introduced HTML5 and CSS3 to Magento applications
- Defined and authored the company's best practices and coding standards document for front-end development
- Worked closely with IA and Creative departments on defining new and effective user experiences
- Worked closely with backend development team on front-end integration points
- Provided technical direction for clients on front-end hand-off projects
- Utilized text replacement technologies such as Typekit, Cufón, sIFR
- Skinned and integrated custom Magento themes
- · Object-oriented JavaScript development
- Responsive CSS
- Parallax UI Development

- Converted Photoshop documents into HTML and CSS templates
- Wrote custom CSS reset framework

Tech Stack: jQuery, PrototypeJS, LESS, CSS3, Magento, OfBiz, .NET Web API